Harold Christy Schwalen papers, 1896-1967 (bulk 1919-1965)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Subgroup V: Water Resource Studies
  - Series XXIV: Water resource projects, 1919-
    - Colorado River Project, Indian lands development. 1952 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Colorado River Project, Maps. (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Colorado River Project, Salt deposits and Virgin River. 1926 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Colorado River Project, Senate Bill S728. 1927 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Colorado River Project, Water rights: reports and papers. 1924-1958 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Colorado River Project, Water supply studies. 1928-1956 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Golder Damsite, Canada del Oro. 1961 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Gila River Valley Project, Correspondence. 1925-1941 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Gila River Valley Project, maps. (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Gila River Valley Project, printed material. (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Gila River Valley Project, reports. 1947-1950 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Gila River Valley Project, settlement opportunities. 1946 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Gila River Valley Project, water analysis. 1923 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Gila River Valley Project, Well logs and pump tests. 1934 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Midvale Farms Project, maps. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Midvale Farms Project, Reports and notes. 1946 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Midvale Farms Project, Well logs and pump tests. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Mohawk-Wellton Irrigation District. 1951 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Painted Rock Reservoir. 1950 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Papago Reservation, Climactic conditions. 1934 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Papago Reservation, Irrigation development report. 1911 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Papago Reservation, maps. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Papago Reservation, Papago Farms, Notes. 1958 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Papago Reservation, Senate Report #1823. 1952 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Papago Reservation, Well logs and pump data. 1934 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Papago Reservation, Well logs and pump data. 1958 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Queen Creek Irrigation District, maps. (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Quenn Creek Irrigation District, Well logs and pump data. 1935 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Rillito Project. 1951-1958 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Roosevelt Irrigation District, maps. (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Roosevelt Irrigation District, Reports. 1932 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Roosevelt Irrigation District, water analysis. 1938 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Roosevelt Irrigation District, Well logs and pump data. 1933 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Roosevelt Irrigation District, Well logs and pump data. 1933 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Salt River Project, history. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Salt River Project, maps. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Salt River Project, water development. 1930 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Salt River Project, runoff. 1902-1945 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Salt River Project, water analysis. 1943-1946 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Salt River Project, water analysis. 1934-1943 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Salt River Project, water storage. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Salt River Project, water use estimnates. 1939- (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Salt River Project, well logs and pump data. 1936-1951 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - White tanks flood control & irrigation project. 1941 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - San Carlos Irrigation District, crop reports. 1956-1965 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - San Carlos Irrigation District, history. (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - San Carlos Irrigation District, well tables. 1928- (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - San Xavier Reservation, collecting pipeline. 1938 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - San Xavier Reservation, history of well development. 1930 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - San Xavier Reservation, maps and charts. (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Yuma Auxiliary Project, contract. 1949 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Yuma Auxiliary Project, cost tabulations. 1950 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Yuma Auxiliary Project, crop production reports. 1953-1955 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Yuma Auxiliary Project, history. (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Yuma Auxiliary Project, maps and specs. (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Yuma Auxiliary Project, water consumption. 1934-1945 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Yuma Auxiliary Project, well logs and pump data. 1919 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Yuma-Gila Irrigation Project, preliminary study. 1935 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Yuma-Gila Irrigation Project, status of water users. 1961 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Series XXV: Flow records, 1906-1958
    - Critical groundwater areas in Arizona. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Flow records stations. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Peak runoff analysis. 1956 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Rating table for meter #33. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Arivaipa Creek (Feldman). 1919-1921 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Benson Canal. 1921- (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Canada del Oro. 1916-1917 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Canada del Oro. 1920-1921 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Canada del Oro. 1922 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Canada del Oro. 1923 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Canada del Oro. 1925 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Canada del Oro. 1926 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Cave Creek. 1921-1923 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Centennial Wash. 1923-1925 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Cochise County flood chart. 1940 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Duncan Valley. 1923-1939 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - East Turkey Creek. 1920-1923 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Eloy Valley. 1923 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Eloy Valley. 1949-1950 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Flowing Wells. 1926-1927 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Fort Lowell ditches. 1911 (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Gila River at Winkleman. 1922-1927 (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Gold Gulch at Bowie. 1920-1924 (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Hemenway water levels. (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Leslie Canyon flood. 1914 (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Portal ditch at Paradise. 1920-1921 (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Post Creek at Ft. Grant. 1920-1921 (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - rillito Creek at Sabino Canyon. 1952 (Box 34, Folder 28)
    - Rillito River at Oracle Bridge. 1914-1916 (Box 34, Folder 29)
    - Rillito River at Tucson. 1913-1915 (Box 34, Folder 30)
    - Rook Creek at Light. 1920-1921 (Box 34, Folder 31)
    - Round Valley. (Box 34, Folder 32)
    - Sabino Canyon. 1906-1958 (Box 34, Folder 33)
    - San Simon Creek, San Simon. 1919-1925 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - San Simon Creek, Rodeo. 1920-1925 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Santa Cruz River, Bank control and channel alignment project. 1933 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Santa Cruz River, Bank control photographs. 1924-1950 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Santa Cruz River, flood. 1917 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Santa Cruz River, flood. 1930 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Santa Cruz River, floods. 1930-1937 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Santa Cruz River, flood. 1940 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Santa Cruz River, flood photographs. 1965-1966 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Santa Cruz River, flood. 1967 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Santa Cruz River, flow. 1939-1942 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Santa Cruz River, Groundwater development. 1938-1954 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz basin maps. (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Santa Cruz River, seepage (Tucson/Sasco). 1917 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Santa Cruz River, soil moisture samples. September 22-23, 1939 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Santa Cruz River, physiography. (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Santa Cruz River, Eloy. 1916 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Santa Cruz River, Eloy. 1917-1919 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Santa Cruz River, Eloy. 1920 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Santa Cruz River, Eloy. 1921 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Santa Cruz River, Eloy. 1922 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Santa Cruz River, Maricopa. 1918-1919 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Santa Cruz River, Maricopa. 1921 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Santa Cruz River, Maricopa. 1922 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Santa Cruz River, Patagonia/Sonoita Creek. 1938 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Santa Cruz River, Picacho. 1918 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Santa Cruz River, Picacho/Maricopa. 1916 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Santa Cruz River, Redrock. 1923 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Santa Cruz River, Redrock/Sasco. 1916 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Santa Cruz River, Redrock/Sasco. 1917 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Santa Cruz River, Redrock/Sasco. 1918 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Santa Cruz River, Redrock/Sasco. 1919 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Santa Cruz River, Redrock/Sasco. 1920 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Santa Cruz River, Redrock/Sasco. 1921 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Santa Cruz River, Redrock/Sasco. 1922 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Santa Cruz River, Redrock/Sasco. 1923 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Rillito. 1916-1917 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Rillito. 1921 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Rillito cumulative totals. 1917-1924 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Rillito runoff. 1948 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Sasco. 1925 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Sasco. 1926 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Tucson. 1905-1912 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Tucson. 1916 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Tucson. 1921 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Santa Cruz River, Santa Cruz/Tucson. 1924 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Santa Cruz Valley, Sonora, calculations, notes, and maps. 1941 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Santa Cruz Valley, Sonora, photographs. 1941 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - West Turkey Creek at light. 1919-1925 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Whitewater Draw at Rucker. 1920-1925 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Wood Canyon at San Simon. 1920-1923 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Series XXVI: Climatological Data, 1915-1944
    The series contains figures and charts on all types of weather conditions. In addition, there are weather reports collected by the U. S. Dept. of Agriculture.
    - Evaporation, University of Arizona. 1914 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Evaporation Studies, Mesa, Yuma, Willcox. 1915-1940 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Evaporation Studies, Roosevelt lake. 1915-1936 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Meteorological records, Arizona miscellaneous. 1922-1942 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Meteorological records, Tucson. 1933-1934 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Meteorological records, Yuma, Mesa, Willcox. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Movement of soil moisture on Bare Plat studies. (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Movement of soil moisture on Bare Plat studies, Arizona. 1933-1934 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Movement of soil moisture on Bare Plat studies, forecasting. (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Movement of soil moisture on Bare Plat studies, Gila river watershed. 1876-1944 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Movement of soil moisture on Bare Plat studies, S.E. Tucson. 1914 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Precipitation and snowfall in Arizona/New Mexico. 1941 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - San Carlos project. 1930-1944 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Snow, Evaporation studies Gila watershed. 1940-1942 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Snow, Surveys Gila watershed. 1913-1939 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Snow, Surveys Gila watershed. 1914-1954 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Southeastern Arizona weather. 1938 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Temperature charts, Gila watershed. (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Winter storms in America. 1915- (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Daily weater reports, Lees Ferry. 1934-1936 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Daily weater reports, Mesa experimental farm. 1917-1941 (Box 38, Folder 2-6)
    - Daily weater reports, Roosevelt. 1919, 1925 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Daily weater reports, Tempe date farm. 1939-1940 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Daily weater reports, Yuma date orchard. 1928 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Daily weater reports, Yuma evaporative station. 1917-1941 (Box 38, Folder 10-13)
    - Daily weater reports, Willcox. 1917-1936 (Box 38, Folder 14-16)
    - Weater reports, Yuma citrus station. 1920-1941 (Box 39, Folder 1-5)
- Subgroup VI: Supplemental papers and photographs
  - Series XXVII: Addresses and reports
    Includes typescript and manuscript addresses, reports and articles written or given by Schwalen and others.
    - Address for Presentation at Phoenix, Arizona, Hearings Held Under Authority of the McFarland Resolution (S.155, as ammnded by S. Res. 304). Typescript (mimeograph) by H. F. McPhail. August 1 or 2, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Analysis of Flow-Duration, Sediment-Rating Curve Method of Computing Sediment Yield. United States. Interior Dept. Typescript (photocopy). April 1951 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report. Western Regional Cotton Mechanization Project W-24. Typescript (photocopy). 1955 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report. Western Regional Cotton Mechanization Project W-24. Typescript (photocopy). 1957 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report. Western Regional Cotton Mechanization Project W-24. Typescript (photocopy). 1958 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Arizona Power Requirements. Presentation by John T. Kimball. American Society of Civil Engineers, Phoenix, Arizona. April 24, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Classification and Correlation of the Soils of the St. Johns Area, Arizona. Typescript Ms by E. N. Poulson. 1939 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Colorado River - Past and Futue. Presentation. American Society of Civil Engineers, Phoenix, Arizona, typescript (ditto) by H. F. McPhail. April 23-26, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Consumptive Use of Water in the Irrigated Areas of the Upper Colorado River Basin (provisional). United States Dept. of .pa Conservation Service. Typescript by Harry F. Blaney and Wayne D. Criddle. 1949 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Current Developments in Water Law. Address of Edward W. Clyde, Before the Briefing Conference on Water Resources in Washington, D.C. May 23, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Development of Water Resources in the Southwest. Presentation. Joint Meeting of the Western Section of the American Society of Animal Production and the Western Division of the American Dairy Science Association, Sol D. Resnick. July 13, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Development of Water Resources Past, Present and Future. Typescript (ditto) by Robert E. Moore. 1966 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Discussion on Safe Yield of Groundwater Reservoirs. Typescript Ms by G. E. P. Smith, N.D. (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Drilling Operations at Marble Gorge Damsite. Typescript Ms. (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Engineering Report on Plans and Cost Estimates of the First Unit, Gila Valley Project, Arizona. United States. Interior Dept. Typescript Ms (carbon). 1934 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Estimate of Cost of the Proposed Sabino Canyon Dam near Tucson, Arizona for the Game and Fish Dept. of the State of Arizona. Typescript (photocopy). 1960 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Financing Irrigation Districts. Typescript Ms (carbon) by W. W. Lane. 1936 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Flood Control Report, Sabino Canyon, Pima County, Arizona. Typescript Ms. 1936 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Geology and Hydrology Gila River Indian Reservation. Typescript Ms. 1936 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Gila Project. An Irrigation Study on the Yuma Mesa. Typescript (mimeograph). 1945 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - The Gila Project. Typescript Ms (carbon) by George Tank. 1947 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Glimpses of the Work of the Cooperative Hydraulics Laboratory. The U.S. Department of Agriculture Soil Conservation Service and The California Institute of Technology. Typescript (photocopy). 1944 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Ground-Water Status Report: Yuma Area, Arizona, California. U. S. Bureau of Reclamation. Typescript (photocopy) by T. H. Moser. 1972 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Hearing held in Safford, Arizona, Before U. S. Army Board of Engineers, with R. E. Cruse, Captain, Corps of Enginers, presiding, on Proposed Upper Gila River Flood Control and Watershed Protection. Typescript Ms (carbon). September 29, 1937 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - History of Runoff Investigations and Development of Storage in Arizona. Typescript (mimeograph) by Wilbur L. Heckler. 1955 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Limitation in the Development of Groundwater Reservoirs in the Southwest. Typescript Ms (carbon) by Harold C. Schwalen. 1955 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Lyman Dam Irrigation Project Report. Typescript Ms (carbon) by W. W. Lane. 1930 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - North American Water and Power Alliance. "The NAWAPA Story." Typescript (photocopy) by Ralph M. Parsons Company. 1967 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Paper on the Activities of the International Boundary and Water Commission on the Lower Colorado River. Presentation before the Pacific Southwest Federal Inter-agency Technical Committee, San Diego, California. 1952 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Plastered Concrete Tank, Plan A155. University of Arizona. College of Agriculture. Typescript (photocopy). 1965 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Preliminary Study of Watershed Management and Water Yields of the Upper Gila River. Typescript (photocopy) by Hugh G. Calkins. 1938 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Progress Report of Infiltration Studies on a Number of Southern Arizona Soils. United States Dept. of Agriculture Soil Conservation Service. Typescript (photocopy). 1939 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Proposed Research Program for the Institute of Water Utilization. University of Arizona. Typescript (mimeograph). 1955 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Queries for the Following Data Relative to Check Dams in Haines Canyon. Typescript (carbon). 1916 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Report of Survey of a Dam Site and Reservoir on the Santa Cruz River. Nogales Chamber of Commerce. Typescript (carbon). 1932 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Report of Biennial Convention. Western Irrigation and Drainage Research Association. Held at Logan, Utah. 1929 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Report on Silt Studies on the Gila River in 1917 and 1918. Typescript Ms (carbon) by G. E. P. Smith. 1920 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Report on Survey, Flood Control, Gila River and Tributaties. U. S. Engineers' Office, Los Angeles. Typescript Ms (carbon). 1945 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Report on the Proposed Improvement of the St. David Irriga tion System. Typescript Ms (carbon) by M. R. Lewis and Harold C. Schwalen. 1930 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Report on San Carlos Project, Arizona. Vol. 1. Typescript Ms (carbon) by C. C. Fisher. 1920 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Report on San Carlos Project, Arizona. Vol. 2. Typescript Ms (carbon) by C. C. Fisher. 1920 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Report on the Water Supply of the Post Project in the Santa Cruz Valley, Arizona. Typescript Ms (carbon) by D. W. Murphy. 1920 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Report on Upper Gila River Investigation. Typescript Ms (carbon) by C. C. Fisher. 1930 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Report to State Loan Board on Lands Suitable for Inclusion in the Lyman Project. Typescript Ms (carbon) by J. A. Fraps. 1933 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Report on Waterworks System, Phoenix, Arizona. Typescript Ms (carbon) by Black and Veatch Consulting Engineers. 1928 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Report of the Power Committee. Arizona Section of American Society of Civil Engineers. Holograph Ms. 1934 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Report of the Second Conference of Irrigation and Drainage Investigators of the Experiment Stations of the Western States and the Division of Agricultural Engineering, Irrigation Investigations, United States Department of Agriculture. Typescript (mimeograph). 1927 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Report on Available Ground Water Supply and Possible Irrigation Development near Willcox, Arizona. Typescript Ms (carbon) by Quinton, Code & Hill, Consulting Engineers, Los Angeles. 1928 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Report on Silt Investigations, Gila and San Juan Rivers. Typescript Ms (carbon) by W. R. Parkhill. 1919 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - San Carlos Project - Arizona. Report on Gila River and Estimate of Ground Water Supply. Typescript Ms (carbon) by Paul V. Hodges. 1936 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Soil Survey and Classification Chui Chiuschu Area. Portion of Papago Indian Reservation, Arizona. Typescript (mimeograph) by W. G. Harper. 1934 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Soil Survey and Classification, White Lands of San Carlos Project, Arizona. Typescript (mimeograph) by W. G. Harper. 1934 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Snow Surveys, Sublimation of Snow, and Forecasting Water. Typescript (mimeograph) by G. E. P. Smith. 1947 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Some Defects in Western Water Law. Presentation at the Annual Convention of the Association of Western State Engineers, Wells A. Hutchins. 1941 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Some Elements of the Economic Design of Wells and Pumping Plants. Typescript Ms (carbon) by M. R. Lewis 1931 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Study of Cost of Producing Farm Products, Graham County, Arizona, typescript Ms (carbon). 1918-1925 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Test Wells Lyman Irrigation Project. Typescript Ms (carbon). 1940 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Tests of Turbine Centrifugal Pumps. Typescript Ms (carbon) by F. L. Bixby. 1915 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Underground Tile Drainage Systems. Typescript Ms by Clyde Shields. 1952 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Upper Gila River Basin Report. Typescript Ms (carbon) by Technical Committee. 1940 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Upper Gila River Watershed, New Mexico and Arizona. Appendix Supplement to Survey Report. Typescript (mimeograph). 1948 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Water Supply of the Casa Grande Maricopa Pumping District, Pinal County, Arizona. Typescript Ms (carbon). 1942 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Water Supply Reports on Irrigable Lands, Santa Cruz River Valley. Typescript Ms. 1953 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Watershed Handbook. Typescript (mimeograph) by U. S. Forest Service. 1924 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Series XXVIII: Legal documents on water-related topics, 1921-
    - Acts relating to water and groundwater. 1937-1954 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Arizona state building code, Correspondence. 1951-1952 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Arizona state building code, S.B. 90; Ms and annotated copy. (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Colorado River project. 1929- (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Court cases: Pima farms vs Henry Proctor, J.B. and L.D. Parker vs Grace and L.B. McIntryre, and E.C. Adams vs Salt River Valley Water Users' Assn. 1926-1957 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Court cases. 1947-1952 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Court cases: State of Arizona vs. L.S. and Fannie Steen, Tom G. and Mary Bristor vs A. D. and Lula Cheatham, W. W. Jarvis vs the State Land Dept., and Winters vs United States 1953-1970 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Existing legilsation concerning water rights. (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Irrigation district laws, Arizona. 1933 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Legal aspects of water and the California water plan. 1954 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Little Colorado River water rights. 1921 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Mexican laws relating to water. (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Soil conservation district law. 1954 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - State water law in the development of the west. 1943 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Water rights, general information. 1944 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Series IXXX: Miscellaneous studies, 1921-
    - Adobe construction, correspondence. 1935-1936, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Adobe construction, mechanical analysis of soil. (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Adobe construction, notes and charts. (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Adobe construction, papers and reports. 1935-1936 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Adobe construction, printed articles. (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Aquifer parameters. 1968 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Asphalt temeratures. (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Bermuda grass and golf course irrigation. (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - C.R. Sutton air pump. (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Desert erosion letters, Earl H. Morris and H.H. Chapman. 1933 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Earth cracks. (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Electro reclamation. (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Irrigation districts and water companies in Arizona. (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Irrigation pumping plants in Arizona. 1944 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Rainwater collectors correspondence. 1953-1967 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Rainfall and tree ring growth. (Box 45, Folder 16)